保險。
早晨。
冇方法。
有冇異議？
陳振英議員。
誒，青委會議。
並獲提名委員會設立。
噉啊！而家先請委員提名。
啊！屏幕屏幕提名嘅委員李哲林。
陳振英。
有提名咧，需要由一位委員口頭作出。
二零一六年，銀行業披露修訂規則。
並需由最少另外一名委員口頭獲議。
噉啊，根據議程咧，係第一項咧就係誒要選舉我哋小組委員會嘅主席。
同埋二零一六年銀行業指定獲豁免壓記類別修訂公告嘅小組委員會咧，而家開會。
噉啊，根據內務守則第二十二條同埋附錄嘅選舉程序咧，而家請委員提名主席一職嘅人選。
以前。
唔信。
哦。
而。
產生咩？
啊！
都唔會聽我嘢。
接受啊，唔該，OK。
啊，仲有冇其他提名啊？
OK，誒，多謝國家機。
誒啊！陳總，你接唔接啦？
唔係，佢由佢自我提名，跟跟住就可以。
如果冇其他提名咧，就。
咁而家咧就誒未有人獲議，但係亦都冇其他嘅提名。
咁咪請阿陳議員咧上嚟繼續主持會議啦，唔該曬。
嗱，我哋個誒有關程序咧，就係必須一位提名同埋一位和議嘅。
可以請佢。
Good morning.
就算。
咁可以。
呢度唔使啦。
公子選好坐席。
Deborah Cam。
咁好誒。
好啊，誒。
誒，其他委員咧。
而家先請誒有關嘅政府官員入嚟啊！唔該。
而家想問下各位委員，有冇需要誒提名呢個副主席？
如果大家冇意見，噉我哋就誒決定誒唔選副主席啦。
誒銀行政策方面嘅主管朱兆雄先生，銀行政策方面嘅高級經理張錦文先生，仲有律政師方面嘅代表，高級政府律師黃安敏女士。
要及風險緩解標準。
由於喺實施上述保證金要求以及風險緩解標準嘅時候，
首先係二零一六年，銀行業披露修訂規則，簡稱披露規則。
我會先簡單介紹兩項附屬法例，然後再邀請金管局嘅同事作補充。
各位，巴賽爾委員會係設定銀行監管標準，以鞏固金融穩定嘅國際組織。
即是二零一六年銀行業披露修訂規則，以及二零一六年銀行業指明和豁免壓記類別修訂公告。
個簡介啦，好唔該曬誒，多謝委員會邀請我哋出席今日嘅會議啦，向大家展述兩項為實施最新嘅國際銀行監管標準而制定嘅附屬法例。
呢項修訂嘅目的有三個：第一，將巴塞爾銀行監管委員會喺二零一五年發表嘅最新披露規定適用喺本地嘅註冊認可機構。
香港作為委員會嘅成員，以及主要嘅國際金融中心，我哋有責任採納呢一啲嘅披露要求，以確保認可機構所作出嘅監管披露符合國際標準。
修訂公告旨在回應業界嘅訴求，豁免同場外衍生工具交易提供開倉保證金相關嘅額記，方便銀行業執行最新嘅國際保證金標準。
第二，因應巴塞爾委員委員會喺監管一致性評估計劃裡面嘅建議，規定認可機構需要就弱光嘅主要監管資本以及共光比率作出季度披露。
建議嘅新披露規定適用喺本地註冊嘅認可機構。因應呢一項新嘅規定，有關境外註冊嘅認可機構嘅披露規定咧，亦都會作出若幹屬於定義性質嘅相應修訂。
認可機構喺進行場外衍生工具交易中，與其對手方交換嘅開倉保證金，會構成銀行業條例第119A一條所限制嘅壓記。我哋需要作出相關嘅豁免，以免認可機構違反有關嘅規定。
第三，修訂現行規則中有關本地註冊認可機構嘅財路財務披露條文，刪除當中同認可機構現時喺公司條例底下需要遵守嘅相關財務彙報準則重複以及不一致嘅地方。
現時喺本地註冊嘅認可機構，如果喺個資產上邊設定押記，即受到銀行業條例第119A條嘅規管。根據第119A二條，除非另獲豁免，否則認可機構喺某一啲嘅情況下咧，係不得設定押記嘅。
誒好噉，我先介紹下今日出席嘅政府同埋有關當局嘅代表啦。有財經事務及副務局啊，首席助理秘書長啊張怡女士啦，助理秘書長啊嚴君樂先生，香港金融管理局助理總裁銀行政策方面嘅簡嘉琳女士，Miss Karen。
高級政府律師吳文俊先生同埋政府律師黃樂敬先生，首先多謝你哋今日出席呢個會。噉我諗而家首先就想請政府方面睇下邊位啦，負責先簡介下誒呢兩條條例內容嘅情況，好唔好啊？係啊，多謝主席。張副，我首先除咗。
除咗披露規則之外，我哋亦都制定咗《二零一六年銀行業指明獲豁免額記類別修訂公告》，簡稱《修訂公告》，以便實施由巴賽爾委員會以及國際證券事務監察委員會組織所制定有關非經中央結算嘅場外衍生工具保證金要求而。
Karen。
附屬法例可以喺今年嘅三月生效。多謝。
好，我真係請阿簡女士作一個補充。係，阿。
誒雷雷曼啊，同埋國商事件之後咧，我相信咧，我哋又好擔心呢一啲嘅闊面咧。
O.K. 啊？請問誒政府嗰邊仲有冇其他嘅代表想再誒補充發言？
市場 disciplin on the banks, but can also benefit stronger banks in terms of cost of funding and reducing uninformed concerns in times of stress.
一 lack of clear comparable information about banks' risk profiles and exposures, and that arguably fuelled concerns over even strong banks' financial health.
所以，The Banking Disclosure Amendment Rules，as Mr. Cheng has noted，have been designed to incorporate the Basel framework and these perceived benefits into our local regulatory disclosure framework for banks.
令到佢嗰個資產咧嘅誒值咧，或者佢交易嗰個值咧係大過佢銀行規定嘅值。嗱呢個兩個咧，我吸取翻即係我哋慘痛嘅經驗啦，嚇包括係。
我諗呢條條例咧係為咗切合巴塞爾嗰個披露規定嘅，噉我我我相信係重要嘅。但係我有一個係問題想問翻咧，有關於嗰個披露規定作出嗰個。
誒誒exemption，即係話佢喺一啲所謂場外交易嘅衍生工具入邊咧，佢係豁免咗佢。呢個第一，第二就係一啲有關於係押記嘅，即係話係佢就翻嗰個佢嘅資產咧，係作出一啲押記，即係話佢有個共鳴。
主席喺制定兩項附屬法例嘅時候咧，金管局已經充分諮詢咗銀行業界嘅意見，並且得到業界嘅支持。上述兩項附屬法例旨在完善而家誒有關銀行業嘅監管，有令銀行體係嘅穩定發展。咁喺完成相關嘅立法程序之後，我哋希望兩項嘅。
Thank you very much, Chairman. I think it might just be helpful if I mentioned one or two thoughts on the benefits which the Basel Committee is actually trying to achieve. So these revised disclosure standards are part of the Basel Committee's overall initiative to address issues identified in the global financial crisis, where there was a
所以在擬訂修訂標準時，監察委員會致力於提升披露的統一性和可比性，於銀行間及各司法管轄區間。他們是透過規定更廣泛使用標準化模板及資訊須於季、半年度或年度披露，以及讓使用者更容易找到相關資訊。
Easily, the revised standard provides for Pillar Three regulatory disclosures to be presented in a standalone document or a discrete section of the bank's financial statements. So, if users such as analysts and rating agencies can obtain a clearer, more reliable picture of a bank's risk profile, this should have advantages in terms of
目。
啊！
with the other.
唔該，Miss Carinham。
Their profile for credit risk, market risk, operational risk.
諮詢乜嘢嘅評估，同埋一啲風險嘅評估。
或者我請誒金管局嘅同事講一講我哋諮詢嘅內容咧。
The exemptions are very very narrow and not for OTC derivatives. They're really for very small institutions where.
to protect banks for losses that they may suffer as a result of market movements and counterparty default on derivative contracts. In terms of exemptions from the disclosure rules.
冇啦，噉我而家不如誒邀請各位委員提問啦。噉啊，因為其實我哋人數都唔多，咁不過提問第一輪可以先誒五分鐘連問連答先。咁大家但可以多次提問嘅。咁首先誒想提問嘅郭嘉琪議員，主席跟住係姚崇業議員，唔該。好誒。
係咪真係保障到投資者或者存户嘅利益？噉我聽到誒政府做嘅諮詢咧，就係銀行業嘅同意嘅。咁銀行業同意咧，就可能基於佢自己嗰個業界嗰個利益嘅啫。喺保障誒投資者或者存户嗰度咧，政府做咗啲乜嘢嘅？
以獲即係以得到一個結論咧，就係今次嗰個附屬法例嘅修訂咧，能夠係切實同埋係能夠保障到小存户投資者同埋一啲冇法子係透過呢一啲嘅複雜嘅公告而確知銀行本身係進行咗幾多高風險嘅投資嘅一啲嘅行。
Thank you, Chairman. I'll try and pick up the points one by one if I can. In terms of creating charges and leverage, the notice is allowing banks to create a further charge over their own assets when they have to.
post initial margin. So, so, so for the margining requirements are not designed to increase leverage. They've already entered into these OTC derivative contracts, the values of which fluctuate over time. So, as collateral for obligations, both sides of those contracts post margin.
So that were there to be a counterparty default, the the the bank that hasn't defaulted has has has collateral from the from from from its counterparty that it can use to to cover any losses. So so the idea of the the margin requirement is actually to provide it's it's allowing the provision of collateral.
Asking them to disclose all of this information is thought not to be terribly useful. And for larger institutions and deposit-taking institutions, retail banks, the provision of this information enables analysts and others to gain a picture.
Picture of the bank's risk profile and its strength. And so, for strong banks, they should be incentivised to make this disclosure to the rest of their abilities because it can help them in terms of demonstrating that they are indeed a strong bank. These requirements indicate the risk profile of the bank. They are asked to talk about
誒。
Bill's has.
The exemption which is in this.
through the banking industry, which we understand very well, but the point is.
Knowing that you have, knowing that you have consultation.
already have a very foolproof protection on the investor and the customer. You have an answer to that particular question.
You haven't actually answered my question. Yes, the assessment as a risk posed on the investor and the ordinary customer of the bank.
proof from the controlling institution, the government or the MA, to make sure that all these exemption.
do not pose further risk on the customer and investor. So I'm asking, how much and what has been done to ensure that.
If we remember the very bitter experience from the Lehman Brothers and also other banks closure, so we need to have
啊！但係有關嗰個公眾諮詢嗰度，我諗可能仲未誒答到啊，郭議員嘅提問，你可唔可以再喺呢度補充多啲咧？反正時間我大把時間，唔使呢個鐘。
usefulness for such institutions, which haven't yet commenced business, to make that kind of regulatory disclosures. That that is the exemption the industry asked for, really.
那那那， doubt was cast upon them because people couldn't get enough information quickly, and so the Basel Committee has sort of designed these rules to to help with that that process.
這應該能讓使用者從這資訊中獲得更清晰的圖像，瞭解這些銀行所從事的業務以及他們所面臨的風險。這一點在金融危機期間顯得尤為重要，因為大量未經充分了解的 speculation 關於銀行可能的資產配置，引發了危機。因此，即使是最強大的銀行也發現
主席，所以，嗯，作為Ms. Cam説，我認為，嗯
Disclosure rules this time round is in in response to industry comment that in the very exceptional circumstances that when an institution is authorised by the MA but not yet commenced business, they need to be exempted from disclosure because from a practical point of view there is not much.
在一個特定的主題。
There won't be very much in the way of disclosure that they could make.
所以，what you mean is that you don't need to have
個情況，但係因為由於個五嘅percent啦，咁亦都係參考咗國際標準，咁所以咧，我哋相信係誒，即係其實係會保障咗銀行之間嘅交易之餘，亦都係保障咗即係消費者嗰個利益嘅。
所以巴爾委員會已經廣泛諮詢，了，有關巴爾標準，的問題，而且他們也舉辦了多場與使用者的交流會。
So, in terms of consultation, these are actually very technical rules. So we have consulted in industry on these. We haven't had a public consultation because it's difficult to see how much benefit might be gained by that purely because of the technical nature of the rules. In terms of the
The exemption that's being written into the rules, as my colleague explained, this is very limited to institutions that have not yet commenced business. So, as they haven't yet incurred any banking risk, there seems little point in making them make these these detailed disclosures because they're.
much wider consultation because the public will not be able to understand fully the legislation and the bills required. I'm sure that some members of the public would would be able to understand, but they they are very technical rules. So this is if you think of this is like a shopping list of rules asking banks to disclose information about the calculation.
Of their risk-weighted assets and the models and other approaches that they use to calculating those risk-weighted assets for one side of the banking capital ratio, the capital adequacy ratio. So they tend to be very technical. I think the Basel Committee actually, their consultation is a public consultation.
And that has been taken into account in formulating the standard originally. And so, when we implement the standard here, the approach is to consult the industry associations. Other other people do do tend to write in. ISDA, for instance, another industry association may write in. Others can write in if they have a particular interest.
主席，或者我補充下誒有關嗰個誒非中央結算場外衍生工具嗰啲保證金要求同埋風險緩解標準咧，其實係經由誒巴賽爾委員會同埋國際證券事務監察委員會組織咧共同制定嘅。噉係一套嘅國際標準，亦都係誒適用於所有誒。
司法管轄區嘅誒認可機構咯，咁所以今次香港咧，其實係將有關嘅標準咧引入嚟香港。咁誒，明白國議員嗰個誒關注啦。咁但係其實咧就誒睇到今次我哋即係豁免嗰個壓記咧，其實係有一個嘅上限嘅。我哋只係豁免咗五percent嘅壓記。
誒，大家交個保證金出嚟。
我哋請金管局嘅同事解解嗰個具體個。好，好，唔該曬。
點咁個時候咧，就知道個壓記嘅重要性咧，仲有冇喺度啦？好唔好啊？
引致到佢哋可以咧，就係誒可以係做多一啲嘅壓記。
因為誒，將來行咗新嘅例之後，佢哋要交換保證金。如果家嗰啲保證金係壓記嘅話咧，就可能咧受到而家現有銀行業條例嘅一個限制。所以而家所講嘅豁免咧，就係講緊我哋現有條例裡面嘅一啲限制嘅一個豁免。
咁呢一度咧，其實正正咧就平衡咗相關嘅風險，因為有關嘅誒，即係開倉保證金咧，其實最主要咧就係牽涉誒銀行與銀行之間，佢哋喺做一個交易嘅時候，譬如如果避免即係一個誒對方可能會由於我唔履行有關合約而蒙受損失，咁對於。
如果對方銀行蒙受損失，其實對於投資者嚟講都係一個損失嚟嘅。咁所以為咗預防啲噉樣嘅情況咧，咁所以咧就係話誒要求我哋要擺低一個嘅誒開倉保證金。咁呢個保證金係誒冇超過五個percent。咁當誒雙方交易萬一我都真係冇履行到合約嘅時候咧。
咁對方唔會有個損失會有限，其實誒正正係為咗即係保證嗰個投資者佢哋誒嗰個誒利益咯。咁個五嘅percent嘅設定咧，其實就係平衡咗兩方面嗰個誒考慮。即係如果我哋誒冇一個上限，即係無限嘅豁免，咁可能會有誒國議員擔心。
啊啊，郭議員啊，阿張秘書長，我想噉樣樣睇呢件事，或者噉樣大家會比較誒委員會比較清晰嘅，因為呢條條例咧牽涉兩樣嘢，第一個咧就係誒Margin嘅保證金，第二個係一個charges壓記，咁咧喺呢個銀行之間交換。
呢個initial margin即係保證金嗰陣時咧，究竟個保證金係咪已經大家交換？Actually將個錢擺咗喺對方户口咧，呢個係最重要嘅。我唔誒想澄清你哋澄清咧個錢係咪已經由譬如A銀行因為要同B銀行做一個交易，互相交換一個保證金咧個錢？
錢係咪已經去到對方户口？咁呢個咧個運作係唔同嘅，因為押記第二樣嘅就係押記。押記嘅意思咧就係我銀行話畀人聽，呢一部分嘅資產咧已經有人有優先權啊嘛。咁如果呢個保證金已經係用一個已經交付嘅形式畀咗對方。
咁現金就冇冇適應㗎啦。如果已經入咗對方，大家都係互相交換咗嘅，咁呢個壓記呢個重要性就有唔同啦。所以我我想誒，不如請當局澄清呢一個所謂嘅exchange of initial margin between A.I. and its counterparty，佢個運作係。
我因應郭議員嗰個問題，我再解釋一下。其實誒，而家我哋誒嗰個二零一六年銀行業指明獲豁免壓記類別修訂公告嘅目的咧，其實係想輔助我哋準備另外會行嘅另一條另一啲誒監管要求嘅。其實。
其實嗰個監管要求咧，就係我哋睇翻一啲國際嘅準則咧，就係話都係參考咗，就係話上次個金融海嘯之後嘅經驗，就係發現銀行之間做咗嗰啲場外衍生工具交易，就佢哋誒嗰個雙方嘅對手交易有好大嘅風險，所以就要求佢哋做呢啲交易嘅時候咧，要去誒。
誒呢個就話我哋其實要求將會，我哋會行咧就要求佢哋要交換呢個保證金，有咗呢樣保證金咧就可以咧減低咗雙方之間嗰個對手方嘅風險。呢一樣嘢咧係有利於誒銀行降低風險嘅，係我哋覺得係誒應該要做嘅。咁誒我哋。
Euro clear啦。
誒誒，例如誒。
第二就係喺個實際運行嗰度，我哋有冇啲？
即係嗰啲結算結算嘅機構。係啦，係啦。嗯嗯。
咧就唔受金管局監管，同埋咧一般都會係用一啲咧國際嘅一啲誒常用嘅託管人，即係未必會係一個香港嘅託管人。例如咧？
即係有啲漏洞，令到呢個協定咧保障唔到，因為所有呢啲協定嘅保障係保障唔係個銀行㗎嘛，你係嗰啲。
唔可以再用嘅，唔可以畀佢哋咁用。基金管局就會係監管埋佢嗰個託管人㗎啦，即係佢佢同埋，你會睇到佢嗰啲誒呢一筆錢個交收。
放錢落去嘅存户㗎嘛，所以呢個先至緊要啊嘛。我明白係相當複雜，呢啲係好技術性銀行之間嘅嘢。但係問題政府或者監管機構就有個責任，除咗睇個協議之外，就睇個將來個保障係咪足夠嘅嚇。
支出諮詢業界嘅時候咧，就收到一個反應，就係話誒。當大家交換呢個保證金嘅時候咧，嗰啲保證金會構成一個壓記，而壓記咧喺而家我哋嘅例裡面咧有個限制嘅。簡單啲嚟講咧，就限咗銀行佢唔可以喺自己的資產咧誒以壓記嘅形。
抵押畀誒另一方咧，係超過佢個誒總資產嘅一定數額嘅，咁變咗就話有呢一個限制咧，就會影響到佢哋將來可以誒同業界。如果我哋行咗呢要互換保證金之後咧，誒嗰個合規情況。
就係即係話可以日誒，從而咧便利到佢哋咧，將來咧有需要嘅時候咧，佢可以咧就係交換保證金去符合將來嗰啲要求，係一個噉嘅情況嚟嘅。即係話其實我哋係要求佢要去交換嗰個保證金。誒誒，主席即係嗱噉我。
我大概或者我咁理解，聽你冇話我錯啦。即係佢哋係交換咗嗰個百分之五最高上限嘅保證金嘅。唔係嗰個，唔係嗰個，只係一個誒最高個上限上限啦。即係呢個當佢啦。即係如果佢要做衍生工具，佢佢佢有機會會用到盡啦。係啦，好啦，誒，甚至咁更高嘅高遠下，可能大家同。
同意咧係十或者十五做保證金嘅，噉佢哋可能喺呢個交易做一百萬嘅交易咧，大家要交換嗰個保證金，甚至去到十五萬、二十萬，係根據佢雙方協定嘅一個數額嚇。明白我我擔心就係佢第二部分，即係話嗰個互換咗個保證金嗰筆錢咧，再可以再做押記㗎嘛。
即係做collectors嗱，誒咁嗰度咧就會唔會即係將佢嗰啲風險係增加咗？因為佢做咗leverage咧，噉佢個風險係會增加咯。即係話到時會唔會到最後，係誒即係嗰個監管唔足夠啫？其實誒誒，我簡單解釋咧就係係誒唔會嘅，因為其實我哋喺新嗰啲。
例嘅裏面咧，都會有一個要求，同埋業界自己都會平衡自己嘅風險咧。而家業界個做法咧，係會將呢啲開倉保證金，因為其實就係話大家未做嗰個交易都唔知係邊一方咧，會係嗰個係會係有賺或者有虧損嗰一方嚟㗎嘛。呢啲錢只係一個保證金嚟啊嘛，所以而家嘅做法咧，呢。
呢啲保證金咧，佢哋會擺喺一個託管人嗰度嘅，擺開咗嘅。咁呢啲錢咧就喺誒將來我哋誒銀行業嗰個要求嗰度咧，就話呢啲錢咧佢哋唔可以誒，除非嗰誒嗰啲係現金啦。如果佢係一啲以係一啲誒證券形式嘅一個誒抵押品嘅話咧，係。
誒係，我哋會係冇誤地放咗喺個託管人嗰度。誒嗱，其實業界自己都會保障自己嘅風險。誒，佢哋評估邊一個託管嘅方式係最合適佢哋咧？呢一個咧，我哋會畀翻一啲誒一個彈性嘅業界嘅個託管人本身。
嘅任何重大變動嘅描述解釋。
誒定義裏面，咁所以咧應該要作出某個限度嘅誒誒闊免。
其實係亦都唔係淨係銀行嘅聲音，我哋聽到嘅係其他存款公司啊，或者其他誒，佢都反映出業界嗰個意見咯。
好誒，主席或者我簡單即係講一講我哋嗰個修訂個內容嗰個概念啦。咁然後誒，即係我再請誒律政司嘅同事或者金管局嘅同事再補充。
會太寬鬆咧，以致於即係可能會誒影響咗嗰個誒投資者利益咧噉。咁調翻轉咧，就係話誒我哋去做諮詢嘅時候，誒業界可能就會反映就係誒。
咁另外咧，我哋就用二A部咧所在嘅新披露規定咧，就會取代咗現行誒披露規則裏面再有監管風險披露嘅第五、第六同埋第七部啦。
係勾畫出其實兩個誒，即係刪除同埋誒增加嗰個部分咧。其實佢嗰個背後嘅理念，點解要做一個咁大嘅修，即係一加一減而唔係喺裏邊修改啊？
律師裏邊加咗好誒一係列嘅誒條文，然之後咧就刪除咗好大量嘅由第三部分到到第七部分嘅刪除，可唔可以先先誒簡單？
即係主席，我諗最大問題咧，我問呢一啲啦，都係話喺嗰個新嗰個披露嘅協議同埋佢容許佢豁免嗰度咧，係點樣令到唔再重演即係當時嘅金融風暴啦，同埋話係有冇啲投資者係保障到呢個？噉我點解問嗰個問題咧？就話。
本地嘅諮詢咧，就係我想知咧，就係本地嘅諮詢有冇，因為巴塞爾嘅協定咧，係佢有一個一次性咧，我哋明嘅。但係喺我哋嘅本地嘅經驗入邊，有冇覺得，譬如舉個例，巴塞爾協議入邊都未必足夠噉，而我哋嘅要求要可能高過巴塞爾協定呢一個？我想問你呢一個啫，其實或者。
誒，政府嗰方面有冇回應啊？張助理秘書長講翻咧，就其實今次嘅標準咧，即係點解會制定呢一啲噉嘅國際標準咧？其實就係誒因應咗即係金融風暴嘅時候咧，所吸取嘅經驗教訓就係話，即係可能銀行與銀行之間究竟佢哋進行咗幾多嘅長外衍生工具嘅交易？可
可能嗰個透明度都係唔夠嘅。咁今次咧就吸取咗上次嘅經驗教訓，咁所以咧就要求就係話你做一啲噉嘅場外衍生工具交易嘅時候咧，雙方應該要會有一個嘅誒保證金，即係誒一個抵押噉樣。咁變咗咧就唔會話突然間有一其中一方咧，譬如佢唔能夠履行。
佢嗰個承諾嘅時候，另一方會蒙受損失。咁呢一個咧，其實係為咗正正為咗保障嗰個誒小存户啊，或者投資者嗰個利益嘅。咁所以呢一套嘅標準咧，其實就係吸取咗嗰個金融風暴嘅經驗教訓啦，亦都睇翻咧普遍咧即係國際間銀行界嗰個做法咧而制定嘅。
咁所以誒，佢制定嘅時候咧，就唔淨係巴賽爾委員會，都牽涉咗嗰個誒國際證券事務監察誒組織咯。咁呢一套嘅誒要求咧，其實誒如果業界同我哋反應咧，就唔會覺得係一套寬鬆容易做嘅誒即係標準嚟嘅。咁所以啊，國議員即係擔心，即係話會唔會？
呢一啲噉嘅標準會唔會導致佢哋而家嗰個誒業務咧，其實更加係困難嘅。噉佢哋提出一點咧，就係啱先就係誒金管局同事解釋咗啦，就話嗰個壓記誒，即係因為由於要做呢一個開倉保證金噉，已經跌入咗我哋銀行業誒規例裡面所講嘅壓記嗰個。
噉佢先至可以咧達到咧呢個保證金即係嗰個要求噉樣，咁所以今次咧其實誒我哋誒做諮詢嘅時候咧，誒我哋跟誒嗰個條例嘅要求啦，就做一個法定嘅諮詢啦。咁誒牽涉咗即係譬如銀行工會啊，或者其他嘅誒存款誒保障嘅誒工會啊噉樣，咁所以。
好誒，咁一係誒，我哋先畀阿姚重賢議員亦都問下佢嘅問題先。因為我諗時間其實唔重要嘅，不我哋又唔計時間啦。等阿姚議員你自由發問啦。唔該，唔該，主席誒，就其實我哋誒聽到有部分業界，譬如銀行界，佢哋就對於呢一次收。
定咧，其實有好大憂慮嘅，又唔似得係你哋所講話，佢哋都即係歡迎，佢哋係覺得個適應上高可能會有啲困難。但係我諗嗱，誒不如噉，因為誒上屆我唔喺度，可能你哋已經誒嚟過好多次，委員會解釋都唔定。嗱，我見到今次個修訂咧，主要就係誒用十六B到到十。
噉，然後我哋就喺嗰個披露規則裏面咧，引入咗新增嘅第二B部。
咁誒，另外咧就我哋最後就修訂咗而家披露規則第三、第六同埋第八條。
以至於誒所披露資料嘅質量保證規定，咁呢一個咧就係第一部分嗰個修訂咯。
尤其是喺適應上高啊，我哋就聽到咧，佢哋就好擔心點樣去適應呢一個修訂。
咁而定明咧有關主要嘅資本同埋供剛比率以及其組成部分嘅季度披露要求。
咁誒，而第二類嘅修訂咧，就係跟誒落實嗰個認可機構嗰個季度披露規定有關嘅。
就係誒點解啊？姚議員頭先提到我哋廢除咗咁多條文咧，其實就刪除咗嗰個重複或者唔一致嘅地方。
咁以反映二零一五年巴塞爾規誒披露規定有關披露頻密程度啦、披露媒介啦以及地點。
修訂嗰啲意見嘅一啲簡單資料，因為我哋收到嘅意見，部分嘅意見咧同你哋講嘅有啲唔同，佢哋整體係。
咁喺呢一方面咧，我哋就修訂咗而家披露規則嘅第十四條。咁主要咧就係為咗新增個披露規則第二A部同埋第二B部裏面咧有關季度披露嘅要求咧，賦予一個效力嘅。
咁誒頭先講到咧，我哋今次嘅修訂咧，其實有三個目的咯。咁誒，第一個目的咧就係為咗即係喺香港實施巴塞爾委員會佢喺二零一五年最新發表嘅有關即係誒銀行機構佢個披露規定。咁喺做呢一啲嘅規定嘅時候咧，噉我哋就喺而家嗰個披露規則裏面咧。
新增咗第二A部，咁裡面咧就概述咗，即係根據嗰個巴塞爾委員會佢最新嘅披露要求啦。每份標準披露模板嘅主要規定同埋佢個披露嘅頻密程度啦，以及嗰個規定量化嘅披露資料要適當噉樣附上認可機構佢喺報告期內所觀察到嘅。
誒第三類嘅修訂咧，就係目的咧，就係為咗避免即係披露規則同埋嗰個誒公司條例底下咧，而家認可機構佢需要遵守嘅若干誒財務披露規定咧，重複嘅地方噉，因此咧，我哋咧就將重複嘅地方咧都廢除咗佢。咁包括咗誒而家規則嘅十九。
至二十二條啦，第三十二至三十四條以及第三十六至四十三條嘅。咁大致上咧，嗰個修訂咧就係噉樣。咁其實就係引入咗，即係誒巴翠委員會嗰個要求啦。噉我哋分別喺二A部、二B部咧就展示咗喺誒第三部分咧。
誒嗱，如果係咁咧，其實對業界嚟講，佢係要由頭適應過㗎嘛，就唔係一個簡單嘅修訂。佢而家直情等於換曬誒裏邊相關披露嗰個部分嘅要求。所以我想問你哋頭先講話諮詢嘅業界咧，可唔可以提供一啲關於誒業界誒佢哋對今次嘅？
其實誒，或者我先講一講啦。咁今次嗰個修訂內容咧，其實就係根據巴賽爾委員會佢所提供嘅我哋所謂嘅標準模板，即係誒standard template。咁所以咧，其實裡面嘅相關嗰個要求啦，包括個披露誒披露嘅誒內容咧，其實係已經標準化咗。噉我哋睇。
睇嚟咧，其實係更加方便咗業界咧，佢作出佢所需要嘅披露嘅。咁變咗而家其實有一套標準嘅披露表，表佢只需要填翻有關嘅資料。咁對於嗰個誒市場參與者，即係包括一啲誒分析員好、誒投資者好，或者其他嘅誒機構或者監管當局都好。
咧，其實係更加清楚咗，即係一目瞭然嘅。同埋我哋要求咧，呢一套嘅文件咧必須要係誒容易識別啦，同埋要獨立分開，即係我哋可以隨時攞到即刻咧一本書仔咁可以睇到咧佢裡面嗰個披露內容。咁其實我哋誒諮詢業界咧就係根據嗰個銀行業誒條例嗰個法定諮詢啦。噉我
好啊！唔該，主席。
阿姚思榮議員嘅。
誒就誒諮詢係咪集中都係做披露修訂誒規例為為主啊？
其實就誒，我哋誒兩，我哋今次有兩個嘅附屬法例啦。咁兩項嘅附屬法例咧，其實都有做到諮詢嘅。
亦都幫我哋反映咗一啲嘅誒意見啦。噉我哋欣應嗰啲要意見咧，其實係作出一啲技術嘅修訂。咁而家出到嚟呢一套咧，其實已經係吸納咗業界嘅意見，再反映出嚟嘅。
一個噉嘅情況，佢哋點樣回應你哋呢方面嘅誒調整？咁誒至於披露嘅誒有關嘅資料內容咧，我誒披露咗之後咧，邊個機構會進行核實？
咁誒，第一個嘅附屬法例咧，就係誒關於嗰個巴賽爾委員會嗰個披露內容啦，以至於個誒增加咗嗰個季度披露規定同埋嗰個同誒即係財務報表方面即係重複嘅地方係刪除，其實呢一套嘅誒內容咧都有做到個諮詢嘅。
我哋諮詢嘅時候咧，除咗話即係嗰個誒修訂嗰個大致嘅框架之外咧，其實我哋有將嗰個相關嘅條文咧，主要嘅條文咧，都同業界咧即係誒分享咗嘅，包括議員而家睇到嘅條文咧，其實我哋係有誒喺做諮詢嘅時候咧，畀埋佢哋睇嘅。咁所以咧，佢哋睇咗呢一啲條文咧。
誒，即係今次嘅調整咧，係誒由半年誒一年咧，即係誒再增加到一個季度噉樣嚇，咁會造成銀行呢方面嘅壓力嘅嚇。噉我唔知道喺呢方面你同銀行之間誒溝通嘅時候咧，即係喺資源上會誒造成咩？
或者係抽查嘅安排，咁避免咧，即係你咁密啦。咁有啲人會唔會即係有啲銀行會唔會就係敷衍啦？噉啊，反正你都咁密，我就隨便按照有關嘅表格填好就算數。咁有關嘅資料你知啦，銀行嘅數據都好複雜嘅，噉啊一般人睇唔明啊嘛。咁呢方面會唔會有呢方面嘅即係抽查安排啦？嚇！
好，嗯，係咪啊，李處長，我講一講，然後誒金管局嘅同事再補充啦。噉，好啊。其實誒今次新增嗰個誒季度披露嗰個要求咧，其實亦都係因應即係巴賽爾委員會個要求嚟嘅。巴賽爾委員會咧，佢誒不時咧會就即係唔同嘅誒司法誒管轄區或者唔同嘅經濟體成。
員佢哋誒入喺遵守即係相關嘅國際標準方面咧，做成點咧，就做一個評估嘅。噉佢哋今次咧喺誒即係就住香港嗰個制度咧，做咗一個有關誒即係監管誒監察嘅一致性評估裏面咧，就發現咧，即係香港個制度咧，可能需要喺嗰個季度披露咧方面再加強。
咁所以應應即係委員會呢一個建議咧，就喺今次裡面咧就引入咗一啲嘅季度披露要求。咁其實呢一啲嘅誒季度披露要求咧，喺其他嘅地方咧，嗰個誒銀行機構咧，其實已經要做緊嘅。噉我哋相信咧，對於銀行嚟講咧，其實就唔係話即係太大嘅負擔。即係當然佢日後即係佢做披露。
睇法。
OK，咁誒，睇下各位委員仲有冇其他問題？
咁定落嚟嘅。好，唔該。咁誒，睇下各位委委員仲有冇其他問題。
如果冇議員提出咧，噉我哋就可以着手到下一步啦。就係誒到。
That their preparation of the financial statements should be subject to, and and also.
如果冇咧，下一個我想問下大家嘅咧，就話關於誒諮詢嘅問題啦。咁有冇需要咧？就話誒，請公眾人士就規則同公告咧，誒提交意見嘅。咁睇下呢度大家有冇咩？
市場嗰個透明度，同埋對於嗰個誒認可機構嚟講咧，其實都有個好處嘅，即係好似誒簡女士頭先睇到啦。噉你誒，如果當嗰個市場對個機構有信心嘅時候咧，其實佢去融資嘅時候咧，嗰個成本亦都會降低。
在 revised disclosure requirement， there is a requirement for the regulatory disclosure to be reconciled back to the audited financial statement， and that also provides a degree of assurance for the disclosed information as well.
同業界誒傾過呢個時間係咪誒足夠畀佢哋準備啊？或者誒，就算係生效咗，會唔會畀一個誒不凡佢哋可以喺誒一個幾個月之後先至做啊？咁唔知有冇呢啲噉嘅誒過渡安排畀佢哋有機會即係適應咧？噉樣，我想問一下。
嘅時候，或者佢填個披露報表嘅時候咧，佢要多填一啲嘅內容啦。咁但係我哋相信咧，即係作為一個誒，即係誒良好管治啦，亦都增加透明度、增加市場誒紀律嗰個角度嚟睇咧，其實銀行咧應該呢一啲嘅資料咧，佢應該其實已經喺度嘅。咁只不過以前可能佢冇需要。
即係特別根據呢一個條例作出披露，而家咧佢要作出一個披露咁解。噉我哋相信咧，當然即係銀行佢可能會有誒，即係需要修訂下佢嘅誒，即係譬如誒電腦系統啊，各樣去令有翻有關嘅誒，即係填報咧更加容易啲。咁咧呢一方面咧，佢會有啲公
功夫要做嘅，咁但係我哋相信咧，嗰個誒即係整體嗰個成本其實就唔應該太多。咁但係更加重要係嗰個得益啦。噉我諗係即係方便嗰個誒市場參與者可以更加瞭解即係有關嗰個機構佢嗰個誒財務狀況啦。咁亦都即係增加咗嗰個誒整體。
好噉啊，第二部分嘅誒姚議員嘅問題，關於誒點樣確保銀行填交嘅資料嘅準確性，或者有冇抽查機制嗰度？誒邊位回應啊？或者我請金管局嘅同事講一講啦，因為誒金管局其實就會就住銀行業佢整體嗰個執行情況咧，佢一定會有個規管嘅。好，唔該。
So in general, we require the authorised institutions to lodge a draft statement to us before they make the disclosure. As far as the quality assurance is concerned, the revised Basel disclosure standards also attach more weight to the importance of.
That quality assurance, and they do it do it by several means. First is that they attach more importance to the senior management of the bank's attestation, that the the internal review and control process for ensuring the quality of the.
Disclosure that is approved by board of directors have been adhered to, and also they will need for the interim and annual disclosures. They will need the internal review and control system to be not less stringent than those.
嗯。
去review誒。
As member can see on
under誒section誒。
So so that is what we aim to achieve under Part One.
就取代咧，我哋逐條逐條過，又或者你哋可以提一提有其他方式咁去審議。我唔知大家委員有冇咩誒意見冇？
啊，section去處，係咯係咯，不如一個section一個section咁去處理好嘛？阿姚議員，你都冇意見嗬？我哋用一個section，好咁誒，而家請。
And as we've mentioned earlier in on page 15, in response to industry comments, we also built in an extra exemption for those exceptional circumstances where an institution is authorised but not yet commenced business.
Part two is actually deals with when, where and how to make the required disclosure by authorised institutions, as well as the provision to enhance the quality assurance of the disclosed information.
三，at the application and section three we have the general application and exemption requirements. Here, the proposed amendments are actually consequential changes to cater for the revised structure of the rules under the Basel standards.
頭先咧，阿姚松賢議員咧，其實問咗一個問題咧，我都想即係當誒問一問嘅。咁誒，因為呢個條例如果生效咗之後咧，原先係預計三月就生效㗎啦。咁誒，即係話銀行填報嗰啲咧，全部都要按三月開始啦，就要按呢個新規定。咁喺個時間上，其實有冇同？
其實我哋就住今次嗰個附屬法例嘅修訂咧，已經即係誒做嗰個諮詢咧。其實已經即係相當一段時間啦。咁呢一段時間咧，我哋相信啲銀行方面咧，其實已經有充分嘅準備。咁同埋正如頭先所講啦，有關嘅資料咧，我哋相信啲銀行咧，其實佢已經有喺度嘅啦。只不過平時咧就唔需要咧。
根據個條例咧，即係作出一個申報嘅啫噉樣。咁所以我哋相信咧，銀行業咧就已經有足夠嘅嘅心理準備咧，去迎接呢一個改變嘅。咁三月咧，其實呢個時間咧就係已經即係喺諮詢嘅時候咧考慮咗即係業界嘅意見啊。咁亦都即係睇咗佢哋嗰個誒準備嘅情況咧。
審議呢個規則同公告條文嘅規定啦。咁因為呢個規則同條文咧就相當之誒技術性嘅，咁而亦都咧嗰個內容誒都幾多。噉我想誒睇下委員同唔同意咧。我哋用即係一個段，即係分一個section一個section噉。
啊，我哋不如睇中英文版啦，我哋一齊睇啦，因為可能中英文嗰個誒，如果大家對個字眼有有唔同意見，可以提。我哋用嗰個mark up copy去誒説明一下，好唔好啊？咁誒，政府嗰度唔知邊位負責誒呢個嗰只？哦，好，阿阿朱主管，咁誒麻煩朱主管你。
我哋用一個section一個section咧，你可以即係一個部分一個部分講，裏邊有啲咩誒誒改動，而唔需要逐條講。如果有個委員睇嗰個section有咩問題咧，可以即刻提出，好唔好啊？唔該啊，朱主管。Okay，誒，Thank you，Chairman，Thank you，Members。So，um，I think，誒，the，誒，maybe，I，will，just，give，誒，give，the，Members。
An outline of what we are going, we are we propose to achieve by the proposed changes. Part one is actually preliminary of the rules, which deal with the definition and overall scope of application of the rules. So and as members can see from page one to page 11 of the markup version of the
Rules, a number of definitions was proposed to be repealed because the reason is that they are no longer used in the revised disclosure requirements, and some of the new definitions on the other hand will be added in order to address the new frequency requirement.
嗯。
OK。
啊！
section eight。
因為我哋興趣。
Section 12， the additional subsection two。
Disclosure items, so that they will have plenty of time to prepare the disclosure.
Section, sorry, page 26, section 8, okay.
Section eight, eight is about I think right to verify right the report.
Discrete sections of the institution's financial statements to facilitate users' navigation for the required information.
and and the other changes in in that section actually presentational in nature without major change in substance to the existing standard.
Of the Basel standard, as Ms. Chan has already said, it includes quarterly, semi-annual and annual disclosures. So that's that will be what we are proposing to achieve under part under the revised Part One of the banking disclosure rules.
On page seventeen, seventeen, section six on location, that is one of the key enhancements that we are proposing for the disclosure rules, and that is to require that all regulatory disclosures should be housed in a self-contained standalone document, or
Page 18 to 20 deals with the required timing for the disclosure, and that actually maybe indirectly answer the question that Chairman raised earlier. The on the first quarterly disclosure for the for the end March 2017 positions, actually we have.
時間、lead time for the disclosure， that means eight weeks。所以that that that is not to say the bank has to disclose on the 31st of March， but the banks will have eight weeks lead time to prepare the disclosure。And the quality disclosure， as we we will see later， only do with very limited regulatory.
Section eight is to do with the enhancement to the assurance quality assurance of the required disclosures. Here, as we see from the new section three, we require one or one or more members of the senior management of the authorised institutions to.
test in writing the disclosure is prepared in accordance with the internal review and internal control process that have to be approved by the board of directors and subsection four requires that in in the case of interim and annual reporting periods where it normally there is a financial statement
Mr. Secretary.
stack two， yes。
但係，任何 enforcement。
好嘛？
create criminal offence.
about enforcement.
do not follow this verification requirement.
paragraph to say if bankers.
So am I correct? Indeed, the enforcement relies on another.
on the causing personal liability to.
any provisions嗰度要liable嘅嘅嘅，即係嘢咧，佢仍然要係liable嘅，所以嗰度係冇變嘅。所以佢呢度只不過係加重佢哋嘅誒，即係誒責任啦，係啦，應明確同埋加重佢哋嘅責任啫。誒，我理解唔知啱唔啱？
To be prepared in those kind of periods, the internal review and internal control processes have to be less stringent than those financial statements subject are subject to. So that's a kind of provisions to aim to enhance the quality.
Yeah, the six actually section that the enforcement section derives from section 60A of the banking ordinance, under which the the MA will make the disclosure rules. So if an AI does contravene any sections of the banking disclosure rules, that
要依個嗱，我我理解咧，就首先咧，第八條核實呢個咧，就加重咗誒，即係A.I.啦，即係銀行啦，佢需要披露嘅準確性啦。佢由原先嘅高級管理人員需確保，佢就加強咗咧佢誒具體應該點樣去執行啦。咁另外咧就係如果係in。
reach of呢啲噉嘅誒disclosure rules咧，佢呢個rules咧只係講disclosure要做嘅嘢，但係銀行整體銀行業嗰個條例裏邊咧，如果佢唔按任何一條條例去做嘅話咧，佢喺另外一啲section，嗰個section係冇改到嘅，即係原先譬如誒喺邊個情況下銀行嘅董事或者
高級管理人員要負責，甚至係有刑責嘅話咧，嗰個部分係冇誒改到嘅。咁只不過咧，呢啲噉嘅新嘅規定係指誒指在咧，就明確佢仲要做到啲乜嘢。如果佢係冇做到啲嘢咧，就仍然係按原來整體銀行業條例。如果你in breach of
page twenty nine.
this grows to the fact.
頻率，以及作為地點的披露。
Well，then，section，12，subsection，2，is，act。
And then, if it is exempted, then
哦，section twenty，yeah，actually，um here，um。
subsection two b, right would allow them not to disclose the calculation, but just
係，主體法例裡面相關嘅物質去進行嘅。好，好，誒，咁麻煩朱主管你繼續啊，唔該。
Would you might explain a little bit about right 2B, 2B about right disclosure of the fact.
which are also consequential changes to reflect the Basel standards in relation to the basis of disclosure, cross-period comparative information.
Going forward, the same will apply to page twenty nine to thirty two in relation to amendment to section twelve to fifteen.
Thank you, Chairman. Section 11, from page 27 to 28 of the markup version, they are just the amendment to the section references that are consequential upon the amendment to the main parts of the rules.
銀行業條例裏面咧，即係個主體法例裏面咧，就住即係佢誒有關誒認可機構啦，包括佢負責人咧。佢如果佢違反即係法例底下嘅任何要求咧，其實已經有一啲嘅罰則嘅，咁亦都係一啲嘅刑事嘅罰則。咁誒呢一啲嘅罰則係冇改動到嘅。咁所以今次咧呢一個嘅附屬法例咧，亦都係以。
many of the disclosures actually the disclosure requirements are associated with the capital standards that the bank has to comply with, and under the capital standards, bank has to calculate the risk-weighted amount for various kind of risk, like credit risk, operational risk and market risk etc. So
for for each type of risk, we have different calculation approaches for different banks of different level of sophistication to calculate. So it may not be the case case that all the required disclosure we apply to a particular bank. So what what what it is trying to achieve is that
A bank will need to disclose which which disclosure requirements is applicable to it, and if if it is the the approach is not applicable to it, it has to disclose the fact. No, I think subsection two is trying to provide exemption, right?
喂。
Am I correct?
唔該，繼續。
So, um.
adds a disclosure requirement.
Requirements in the Basel Standards.
Now we come to the new.
In each division, division one is just preliminary, linking the requirement back to the general application sections in part one. So I will start off from division two.
Division Two covers Sections 16B and 16C, which requires institutions to make disclosure to private users with an overview of the risk management control and risk profile of the of the bank.
Then obviously, because it's exempted already under the capital rules, it can't make disclosure with regard to that approach because it's not using that approach. But but this is adding a disclosure requirement because they now must disclose that fact.
Miss Carin Cam, please. Perhaps I could just supplement. So, the first part of section, the new section two, is explaining that if an authorised institution is already exempted under the capital rules from the requirement to calculate capital requirements for a particular approach.
So, for instance, under the internal under market risk, certain banks, small banks, can be excluded from having to disclose from having to calculate capital for market risk. And if that's the case, they must now state that they are exempted from that. So they have to disclose the fact that they're exempted.
和why and for instance the other one I think would be internal ratings based approach where even if you have a modelling approval some portfolios may not be under that and so now you'd have to explain why all of your portfolios are not under that approach so you have to disclose the negative in fact why you're not obliged to calculate capital under that approach so
Newly proposed Part 2A of the disclosure amendment rules, which start from page 32, 33 of the markup version, that's as we have as said earlier, is the is a core part of this this round of amendments to the disclosure rules. The purpose of which is to reproduce the prescribed disclosure require
And this contains quarterly, semi-annual and as well as annual disclosures that are grouped under six areas of regulatory capital framework, as indicated by the title of each of the division two to seven under the new part. So maybe we'll run through each part in turn and see if members have any particular questions.
Division three, starting from page thirty-five, covers section sixty D to sixty F. That requires AI's institutions to make disclosure on how the figures disclosed in their financial statements link or reconcile with the regulatory exposures. And there are two.
嗯。
So.
division four for example.
More explanation as to the linkage between the two.
deals with AI's disclosure in relation to their civilisation exposures.
the rules by adding the new part two A to the rules.
The next division will be Division Five, running from page 41.
That deals with AI's disclosure in relation to their counterparty credit risk.
and the same approach as we can see will apply to subsequent divisions five to seven, which deal with other risk areas.
And the last division is to do with market risks, so that's sort of cover what we are going. We are trying to achieve by amending.
As I said earlier, a menu of disclosure requirements for for the for for the banks to select based on the approaches they they use for risk rating purposes.
Section Division Six, which runs runs from page 46 to 48, covering sections 16ZE to 16ZI.
Page sixty thirty six to fifty is the division four to division seven of the new requirement under Part Two A. Those are the disclosure requirement relate to specific risk areas.
potential sources of potential differences. One is because of the different scope of consolidation under regulatory versus under the accounting standards. And the second source of differences is the valuations of the of the exposures. So that's the kind of provides
Covering section 16G to 16U requires institutions to disclose information relating to their credit risk for non-securitisation exposures. Those disclosures generally cover information on credit risk management, a breakdown of the credit risk profile of an AI, and there is.
之前嘅。
啊。
And.
啊！
on page，呃，50。
9 to 109.
Part two, part four, which runs from page 60.
from page 67 to 68.
15 regulatory consistency assessment programme as we mentioned earlier, and that is a finding that will make Hong Kong's disclosure framework more in line with the Basel standard.
這些將包括披露，像那些在關係到資本基，它們預期將在下一階段的巴塞爾標準，當T2將被 incorporatet into Part 2A 作為。
A new Part 3A will be added to house any remaining interim financial disclosures which are unique to the first six-month period of a financial year and hence cannot be grouped under the semi-annual disclosure.
Part three, which currently houses the interim financial disclosures, will be amended to house any additional semi-annual disclosures on top of those already covered by Part Two A and Part Two B.
This will include financial disclosure requirements formally included in Part Three, now streamlined to avoid inconsistency and duplication with the prevailing accounting standards, as we mentioned earlier, and also liquidity information disclosures.
We also propose to add a new Part 2B to put in some key key ratios in relation to capital leverage ratios that have to be disclosed on the quarterly basis, and that that is to address a finding by the Basel Committee in their 2015.
是about the annual existing annual financial disclosures, which will undergo similar amendments as in as in part three, so that it will from then on house any additional annual disclosure on top of those already covered by the previous part two A, two B and three, and also.
include financial disclosure requirement streamlined to avoid inconsistency and duplication with the prevailing accounting standards, and other than that, we also propose on page ninety eight amendment relating to the identification of potential proposed systemically important banks to enhance the disclosure in relation to the.
啲。
收息。
Euro.
或equivalent。
誒。
200 billion。
the right to
which would empower HKMA right.
所以我 find that you add subsection two a.
Did you seek the comments from the banking industry on this?
I think two A A seems to be quite similar to the original subsection two, but then two A B.
required disclosure. Yeah, yeah. How does the banking industry respond to this addition?
Sorry, may I ask, section forty-five, C, page ninety-eight, as page nine, ninety-eight, ninety-eight, okay.
Yeah, for two A A seems to be right similar to the original one, but then two A B, right, would empower a very subjective right power to the M A.
I don't think they raise any particular comments on that. And maybe let me explain the the difference. Okay. The new formally in the in the pre-amended versions, the MA can only require an institutions that is tax to make the relevant disclosure.
under subsection three, when it is either designated by the MA as a global systemically important bank, or if the institution on the or on on the last financial year year end has an exposure size of that is that exceeds and.
Okay.
Please go ahead.
咩話咩？
誒，所以誒，從誒。
globally, systemically important.
page 110 to 164 are those.
That this institution is capable of having that significant impact.
But as is using the word reason to believe, right? Then
所以，它其實係just to enable us to fit our regime into that financial stability board regime.
所以，industry被consulted on it. They they understand how the the G-SIB mechanism works. I think so. They recognise that this is aligning the two mechanisms, so that we can reflect the Financial Stability Board requirement.
If I may, yes, we have we have sought the comments from the banking industry. What what we're trying to do here is kind of replicate the global system for identifying global systemically important banks (G-SIBs). And there are various ways to to do that. There is a list published by the Financial Stability Board every November of the the
G-SIBs and they go by size is one of the criterion, but there is also a kind of a supervisory mechanism that you can add a bank to this list of G-SIBs if even if they don't fulfil the size requirement, the supervisor concerned genuinely considers them to be.
所以我們我們reflecting that ability, but this isn't completely unfettered on the part of the monetary authority. We would have to believe that this particular institution would be capable of having a significant impact on the effective working and stability of the global financial system. So, not just Hong Kong's, but the global system.
Would there be any guideline, right, or how how to make sure that right the person who exercise this discretion would have some guideline to follow? Well, well, generally, government officers exercising discretion have to act reasonably. So I think that in looking at this, the monetary
Authority would have to have looked at this institution and considered that some aspect of its risk profile or its business was was potentially systemic globally. So I think you'd you'd have to act reasonably in looking at that. It's difficult to foresee exactly what what it could be because most likely it would come from.
One of the things that already identified size, interconnectedness, complexity. But as I say, the FSB just has this additional category for where a supervisor sees a bank and knows that it's globally systemic to add it to the list. So we'd have to have justifiable reason to believe.
噉啊！
係誒，邊位介紹？
啊！可以繼續誒。
誒三條嗰個闊面嘅，咁誒。
哦，好，嗯，阿阿張張張高級經理，唔該，張生。
Part eight is the part that applies only to overseas incorporated AIs, and this and this round of amendment actually.
我諗，如果呢個誒呢一部分冇問題咧，我哋就想誒，另外嗰個charges嗰個係咪都係應該專門講一次啊？就誒壓記嗰條條例好唔好啊？
誒或者我先講講誒，其實今次嗰個修訂嘅目的咧，我哋係想喺誒現有銀行業條例一九A條嘅限制之上咧，誒。
System Part Five to Seven, which which will be replaced or superseded once we have the new Part Two A in effect to implement the revised Basel standards.
要呢一條誒條例個修訂咧，個目的就係呢一個嘅啫。係誒，其實目的頭先大家都好清楚，而家反而係睇下大家對字眼、具體字眼呢個描述，即係同個立法原意咧，會唔會有咩出入啦？
Are not intended to affect the disclosure requirements of overseas incorporated AIs, but the amendments are consequential in nature. Definitions, terms etc. to be reflected in revised requirements. So
嘅資產超過咗佢總資產值五個percent之後咧，就係限制銀行唔可以再以押嘅形式去抵押佢啲資產㗎啦。除非就係誒嗰啲誒誒押記咧，係得到誒誒喺一一九A。
誒啊！金融誒管理專員可以作出嘅豁免咧，我哋想增加多一個類別嘅豁免嘅啫。呢個誒咁首先要講解一下，就係話一九A而家嗰個限制，佢就限制咗咧銀行當佢喺抵押以押嘅形式抵押佢。
我哋咧就係正如我頭先有誒答一條問題嘅時候有講過啦，我哋就係準備咧就會係施行一啲新嘅一啲監管要求，就係要求銀行喺從事嗰個誒場外衍生工具交易嘅時候咧，要交換呢一個開倉保證金嘅。噉我哋。
之前諮詢業界嘅時候咧，業界就話：而誒呢啲誒誒，支開誒開倉保證金咧，係會構成一個壓記嘅，變咗咧就係誒同而家一一九A條嗰個限制有啲誒矛盾。咁所以咧，我哋因應業界要求咧，而家就係誒誒建議。
就係話誒，附加多一樣獲豁免嘅壓記，就係誒喺係喺場外衍生工具交易誒，去進行交易嘅時候，去交換呢一個誒誒呢一個開倉保證金所產生嘅壓記咧，就係作出一個豁免，主要。
唔該。
即係法律顧問。
多謝主席嘅。
system， bracket。
阿吳生係咪？好，唔該。
咁原先嘅寫法咧，就係。
睇嚟大家都冇冇乜特別，好咁誒。
We noticed that verdicts.
ClearBank S.A. acting as an operator of your clear
而家notice咧就係第二個部分啦，第二條啦。
啊，對唔住，我讀翻英文啦。Charges were in favour of bureaucratic.
由一個 authorised institution incorporate in Hong Kong。
所以誒，為什麼會啲人delete？
咁咧就誒，我誒對住我而家講緊係即係。
好，阿法律顧問，請問你誒就呢個法例嗰度咧，有冇咩誒意見？
由由一個 authorised institution incorporate in Hong Kong is missing in the new amended cross.
好。
麻煩同事。
係啊，係啊。
notice嘅時候係誒。
個麥未開啊，可能。
做，大家委員仲有冇其他嘅問題？
請吳生講先。其實我哋喺草擬誒，今個誒。
法律委員，你覺得係係誒誒，我覺得明白，可以接受。O.K.，無盡一貫好誒。
啊！小院想問多句，頭先有提過嗰啲template咧？誒係咪statutory㗎，定話佢可以選擇㗎？
嗰啲咁誒，所以咧喺個公告嗰度咧係唔需要重複講一次誒，係嗰啲誒壓記係要由嗰個誒。
即係不將B C B S嗰啲template誒migrate過嚟香港呢度咧，究竟香港嘅finance誒A I有冇權選擇唔用呢個template？
誒認可機構係去做嘅，就單單係講嗰個押記嘅性質就得啦。呢個係特登係去誒簡化嗰個草意咯。誒咁其實係一個誒邏輯嘅問題啦。嚇唔該曬。
No, my my point is because I cannot find those template in these revised regulations. So my question is: Are those templates statutory, or are they just for reference? Yeah, they must. They must. They must disclose the templates. Yeah. Yeah.
誒特地係去簡化嗰個草案嘅誒，因為其實誒嗰個誒第一百一十九A條嗰個條文其實係講到話誒嗰啲認可機構咧係唔可以誒訂立壓記啦，除非係誒嗰個誒公告裡面指明。
啊，謝主席。Thank you, members' questions. So there are actually as two kinds of templates. Half of it, half of templates are fixed format. They are called templates. And the other half is more to do with qualitative descriptions, and you can prescribe a very fixed template.
for banks to provide qualitative information like the risk management and controls. So the other half are tables, tables. But even so, they they still have different prescribed sections that they need to fill in. But for the templates which are to do with quantitative disclosures, they do not have a flexibility to change the rules.
如果template就唔係法定嘅，係咪可可以噉樣理解？其實就已經將嗰個將嗰個誒template就已經係。
佢喺場外嘅衍生工具所做嘅規模，好或者係要即係面對嗰個嘅係誒風險係點樣樣嘅狀態咧？誒，我覺得係會有個機制係掌握到，就算你豁免咗都好。
係係以交易計啊，都係要彙報畀喺而家有一個咧，就係資料收集處嗰度嘅。咁所以咧，我哋可以透過嗰誒收集翻嚟嘅資料咧，就可以係監管到而家呢一個市場。
法定要求，咁呢一啲其實已經係根據翻即係個國際組織個嗰個標準嘅模板咧，已經係引入咗喺法例，咁變咗係嗰個法定嘅要求咧，有關嘅認可機構咧，一定要跟翻個內容去填報嘅。
嗰個誒附屬法例裏面啦，咁誒附屬法例裏面咧，其實已經係陳述咗咧，譬如佢誒週年啦，或者佢季度啊，或者佢半年咧，需要披露嘅內容啦，譬如包括佢要加入一啲嘅描述啦，或者佢要新補啲咩嘅資料啦，咁呢一啲全部都已經係。
引入咗喺嗰個法例裏面，即係佢誒所謂嗰個標準模板係啦，因為佢有誒一個內容係喺法定啦嚇。我哋將個內容引入咗嚟啦，已經。誒誒誒，sorry，咩啊咩啊？OK，啊，我見到胡志偉議員好似有問題想提誒，多主席。唔會事，我我唔係委員，不過有個有個有興趣。
趣，都可能又搭過都唔定嘅。其實就喺我哋嘅資料文件裏邊嘅第九段同埋第十段就講，就今次嗰個規定咧，誒第一本身係根據呢一個巴塞巴塞爾二嘅協議之下要做嘅事情嚟嘅。咁但係第十段咧提到就係話咧，係為咗方便業界，即係緩解佢嗰個要面對嘅風險，即係嗰個困難啦。
咁因此咧，就係豁免咗誒，佢喺場外衍生工具所提供嘅開倉保證金相關嘅押記嘅。我想我想請教下咧，就係即係誒，當佢呢一部分係被豁免嘅時間咧，其實係咪有其他相應嘅資料或者係誒資訊咧，係會讓金管局掌握到，讓佢讓嗰個機構。
係誒，我諗呢度係要金管局嘅代表答好。阿阿張張生，麻煩你誒，所想誒澄清一下，其實我哋唔個嗰個目的唔係去豁免佢去交換嗰個開倉保證金，正正係因為咧，我哋準備實施一啲新嘅規則，要。
求就係銀行之間咧，佢哋如果係從事一啲場外衍生工具交易咧，佢就係要去誒交換呢一個開倉保證金。呢個會有一個新嘅要求嚟嘅，但係呢一個新嘅要求咧，同現行銀行業條例一九A條嘅限制咧有少少矛盾。銀銀行業一九。
九A條個限制咧，就係話銀行誒係唔可以。當銀行係喺誒以押記形式去抵押佢嘅資產超過咗佢總資產嘅五個percent之後咧，佢就唔可以再去以押記形式抵押佢啲資產，變咗就係限。
限制咗佢可以誒壓誒去去壓記佢嘅資產嗰個量啊，而誒銀行將來如果要交嗰個開倉保證金咧，呢個開倉保證金咧係會構成一個壓記嘅，變咗有少少矛盾。所以咧，其實而家我哋嗰個豁免係豁免咗誒，其實。
嘅意思即係話係係將喺一九A嗰個限制咧，嗰個上限咧放鬆嗰啲誒，從而咧就便利到咧就話銀行可以再做多啲啊一啲壓記去誒誒便利咧，將來如果佢係要誒做誒要交換個開倉保正急而構成到壓記咧，佢咧。
都唔會抵觸到一一九A條嗰個限制。誒，我諗啊，啊張生，你仲要解釋下咧，就話誒喺銀行做衍生工具呢一啲數量咧，喺監管機構嗰度係咪on and off都有一個monitoring或者睇到佢填嘅表好或者乜嘢？我諗我諗啊，胡議員仲想問呢樣嘢係咪？
係啊，我理解。其實我我我即係可能我問得唔好，因為始終都唔係行家，但係我睇完呢一個文件咧，我就有即係純粹係想知道係咪有機制係會掌握住銀行要承擔個風險，因為始終你一個係豁免咗嗰個原來嘅監管嘅安排㗎嘛。係啦，我哋對於呢一個場外衍生工具交易咧，而家已經實
支咗呢一個咧，就係誒誒一個誒強制嘅，就係佢有一個匯報要求㗎。咁所誒對於一啲咧就係指定咗嘅，我喺香港係係誒誒係重要嘅一啲誒交易嘅產品咧，佢哋而家咧就係做完之後咧，就係以。
唔該曬各位。
飛一飛，因為做嗰個哦，預案。
咁而家我哋要求佢彙報嘅咧，包括就係誒。
噉，二期咧延展到二零一七年三月一號，以便我哋咧有足夠時間咧，首先向內務內會報告啦，然後先至再誒交到立法會度審議嘅。咁睇下各位委員誒有冇唔同嘅意見。
O.K.好多謝各位委員。咁誒，今日要審議嘅事項咧，就誒完結咗㗎啦。噉我多謝大家嘅參與，亦都多謝誒政府啦、金管局啦，同埋律政司嘅代表參與今日嘅會議。噉啊，今日嘅會議就結束啦。誒，唔該曬。
誒唔好意思，用一用翻英文就係誒interest rate swap咧，同埋誒non deliverable forward呢啲產品咧係要誒彙報畀我哋嘅。我哋之前咧係做過調查咧，就係知道咗就係呢啲產品喺香港嗰個市場嗰個誒交易量係最高。
誒，主席冇嘢食，我都想追問一點啫。頭先用用重要嘅交易作為一個詞匯嘅，我想了解下，即係呢個重要交易係有個咩標準咧，係去做判斷。換言之，就話有啲係重要，有啲不重要啦，可唔可以解釋一下呢個部分？我哋係睇翻就係話誒誒嗰種誒產品喺香港嗰個成交。
咁如果佢嗰個衍生工具唔係香港交易嘅，係作為生意嘅一部分嘅話，咁有啲咩機制處理㗎？誒，我哋而家嘅做法就係話誒，你如果嗰個交易喺香港嗰度做，就算佢唔係喺香港入帳咧，都要向我哋匯報，因為我哋一個香港嘅交。
監管機構啦，我係會管翻，就係話香港呢個範圍啦。咁其實呢一個其實都會有一個國際嘅準則嚟嘅，就係外國亦都會有相類似嘅彙報要求，變咗一啲交易。如果喺外國嗰度做咧，佢哋都要係彙報翻畀一啲外國嘅一啲誒嗰啲資料收入處。O.K.明白，唔該曬。好唔該曬各位委員啊。
誒，如果大家冇其他問題咧，因為咧呢個規則同公告咧，本來分別應該喺二零一七年三月三十一日同埋三月三日咧就係起實施嘅。咁但係誒，請委員注意咧，就按一般做法咧，小組委員會咧就要將呢個修訂嘅附屬法例嘅議案咧。
作出預告嘅期限屆滿前咧，要向內務委員會度彙報同埋商議工作。咁由於內會嘅時間限制等等啦，咁如果委員同意嘅話咧，我作為主席咧就會喺二零一七年二月八號嘅立法會會議上咧動議一樣一行議案，將我哋審。